# **Oluwaseun Joseph Olotu**

Block 103 flat 3 plot 56, Iba Housing Estate, Ojo- Lagos, Nigeria

Email: <a href="mailto:seunolo2@gmail.com">seunolo2@gmail.com</a>
MOBILE NUMBER: +2348080643360
Date of Birth: 21th March 1987

#### **SUMMARY**

Senior Java developer with over 10 years of solid IT experience in design, development and maintenance of java application on AWS Highly proficient in developing and deploying a java application on Amazon Web Services (AWS), Glassfish, JBoss and WebLogic. Good experience in the usage of version controls such as GitUp and SVN.

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE:**

## klein Devort (Feb 2006 – Aug 2015) (Web Developer)

- Layout Designs and development using Adobe Dreamweaver CS5
   Demonstrating products to business and Personal customers.
- Lead a team of developers on the conversion and redevelopment of <u>www.precurio.com</u> from Wordpress to an MVC framework Dealt with customers enquiries and procedures and attending to various customer needs.
- Builded a payment process to recharge data subscription using Spring Boot.

### Novajii (SEP 2015 – MAY 2018) (Database Administrator / Senior Web Developer)

- Tested coding software script, monitoring for bugs and performance issues.
- Organized and scheduled system-wide tests to address larger functionality inefficiencies.
- Debriefed development team on potential software errors, and provided user performance reviews.
- Conducted compatibility tests, testing software across a multitude of platforms to ensure universal compatibility.
- Maintained and logged error database, filing user and computer-generated feedback reports and problem alerts.

# Boch System (June 2018 - To Date) (Database Administrator / Senior Web Developer)

Used Oracle APEX 18.0 for designing application structure. Formulated oracle process, data retrieval methods and SQL code blocks. Designed and evaluated applications, and provided architectural input apps. Coded, tested and troubleshot software applications. Conducted unit testing and maintained data extractions and object models. Supported QA activities, test plans and performance enhancement techniques.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

#### **DATABASE:**

Oracle 8i/9i/10g/11g/12c, Microsoft SQL Server, MS Access, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Mysql.

# Languages:

C programming, C++, PLSQL, HTML, JAVA, UNIX Shell scripting, PHP, Python, PLsql, sql, JQuery.

# ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

SWEET VALLEY SEC. SCHOOL (2005) (waec)

Maths (C), English (C), Government (B), Financial- Account (C), Biology (C)

# THE ACADEMIC COUNCIL OF NIIT (2007-2010) (COURSES)

- Designing and Implementing Relational Databases. (SCQ03) (C)
- Web Development (SCQ04) (C)
- Fundamentals of Software Engineering & Linux OS (SCQ05) (C)
- Software Designing & Data Interchange Language (SCQ06) (C)
- Enterprise Wide Applications Developer-(Java Technologies) (SCQ07) (C)
- Enterprise Wide Solutions Architect-(J2EE Technologies) (SCQ08) (A)
- Ecommerce Applications Developer-(J2EE Technologies) (SCQ09) (B)
- IT Project Management in Software Testing & Quality Assurance (SCQ10) (B)

# Mahatma Gandhi University - (India)

Bachelor Degree in computer science (currently ongoing) Distance Learning.

# **MOST RECENT PROJECT:**

S/N	PROJECT NAME	URL	DESCRIPTION
1	SMS PORTAL	https://novajii.com/pls/f?p=107:65:17485492 41794::NO:::	A bulk sms portal.
2	ORE	https://ore.ng/web/	The complete solution for group contribution, lending & investment. It is a web-based platform that provides communities with easy remittance and monitoring of group collections and activities.
3	Riches in Glory Cooperative Multipurpose Society Limited (RIGCOOP)	https://member.rigcoop.com/	Financial Portal that offers services in target savings, alternative savings, reliable and fast loan services for small and medium businesses.
4	INTEGRATION TO EBILLS with Nigeria Inter-Bank Settlement System Plc (NIBSS) ApI	In House	real-time product that facilitates the payment of bills from an account. also include  • integration BVN Validation with Nigeria Inter-Bank Settlement System Plc(NIBSS) API  • Ussd Payment • Bulk messaging service using HTTP API
5	Royal Palm Villa	http://royalpalmvilla.com.ng/	Real Estate website.
6	Yfree	https://yfree.com.ng/	Solution to make online payment for internet services .
7	HRMS Solution (In House)	Custodian Investment PLC	HR self service solution
8	Salvage Portal	http://salvage.custodiansme.com	For selling salvage items
9	Wealth ON	https://www.wealth-on.com/	Multi Level Marketing Solution

## **HOBBIES:**

Soccer, Surfing the web, photography, Working out.